《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
我要你赦免我和我哥的罪名
I want a presidential pardon for me and my brother.
告诉我怎么回事 我就能帮助你
Tell me what's going on, I can take care of you.
只需要把曼宏探员告诉你的话 一字不差地告诉我
All I need you to do is tell me exactly what Agent Mahone told you.
我有工作要完成 有人逼我完成，接电话
I have a job to do, a job that I'm being made to do. Pick up the ph...
等等，留在原地
Wait. Stay right where you are.
站住
Hey.
我知道哪里有五百万元
I know where you can get it. Five million dollars.
-在哪里？ -我可以带你去
- Where is it? - I could take you there...
条件是你不抓我回美国 把我交给警方
...if you don't have to take me to the states, turn me in.
-三张单程票，一个船舱 -太好了
- Three tickets. One cabin, one-way. - Nice.
长官，几分钟后 总统会宣布大赦K
Sir, in just a few minutes the president is going to announce a pardon...
柏劳和斯科菲尔德
...for Burrows and scofield.
我很遗憾地宣布
I regret to inform you, I am stepping down...
我要卸下美国总统一职
...as president of the United states.
我们只剩下一条路可走
There's only one thing we can do.
我们得永远消失
We gotta disappear. Forever.
（E史戴摩 071359-15）
E. STAMMEL
（墨西哥市国际机场）
真重
Very heavy.
里面装了什么玩意儿？
What have you got in there?
七十五磅的 “不关你的事”  ，老兄
About 75 pounds of none-of-your-business, Pedro.
感谢你
For your troubles.
（墨西哥市国际机场）
快开车！快开车！
Go, go, go!
茶包K
T-Bag, T-Bag.
拜托，我需要这些钱
T-Bag, please, I need that money.
-走开，你这浑蛋！ -拜托！拜托！
- Andale, you son of a bitch. - Please, please.
我求求你，拜托！
I'm begging you. Please.
拜托！
Please. No.
（伊利诺州，芝加哥 坦斯朵造船厂）
船何时出航？
What time does the ship leave?
十分钟后
Ten minutes.
我们竟然又要逃亡了
I can't believe we're running again.
-情况不一样了 -是吗？
- It's different now, man. - You think so?
对，我们搞垮了那贱人
Yeah. We brought the bitch down.
-她是自己下台的，林克 -都是因为我们
- She stepped down, Linc. - Because of us.
可是你还是通缉杀人犯
And yet you're still wanted for murder.
你到福克斯河监狱时 记得你说了什么吗？
When you came to Fox River, remember what you said?
你说“我要救你出去” 我还活着，你已经办到了
You said, "I'm gonna break you out of here." I'm alive. You did that.
你要往好处想，就往那想吧
You wanna look for the good, you look there.
走吧，我们去完成你的计划
Come on, let's just finish what you started.
继续来看焦点新闻 卡洛琳雷诺兹不久前K
Continuing with our top story,
caroline Reynolds made the announcement,,,
宣布她要卸下K
,,, just a short while ago that she is stepping down,,,
美国总统的职位
,,, as president of the United States,
我们将提供最新消息K
We'll be bringing you more information...
-喂？ -你没事吧？
- Hello? - Hey, are you all right?
我没事，我刚听到总统的事 这是什么意思？
Yeah, I'm fine. I just heard about the president. What does it mean?
意思是我们该走了
It means it's time to go.
好，什么时候？
Okay. When?
-十分钟，你还要多久才到？ -五分钟
- Ten minutes. How far away are you? - Five.
听着，莎拉 林克和我已经上船了
Listen, sara, Linc and I are on the ship.
时候到了 已经没有后路可退了
This is it. There's no turning back now, so...
我知道你不想过这种日子
I know it's not what you wanted from your life...
不过如果你有兴趣的话 还有一个位子
...but in case you're interested, there is room for one more.
迈克斯科菲尔德 你在邀请我扬帆迎向夕阳吗？
Michael scofield, you asking me to sail off into the sunset with you?
其实是艘货轮 不过是这意思没错
Well, it's more of a freighter, but yes.
我会去的
I'll be there.
待会儿见
I'll see you soon.
她在赖维尔路上往西走
She's heading west on Leadwell.
好，盯着她，我马上过去
All right. Stay on her. I'll be right there.
这是什么鬼？
What the hell's this?
我试过了，老大 你也看到他跑了
I tried, boss. You saw how he just took off.
我只看见一个逃犯 急着想被抓回美国
The only thing I'm seeing is an escaped con who's begging to be taken norte,
好吧
okay. Okay, look.
我们可以打给计程车公司 查出茶包在哪里下车
Maybe we could call the cab company and find out where T-Bag was dropped off.
这才像话 那里有电话K
Yeah, now you're talking. I saw some phones...
要怎样你才会忘记 找到我这档事？
What's it gonna take for you to forget you ever found us?
我到蒂华纳度假的钱还不够
There ain't enough pesos in TJ.
-你确定吗？ -尽管开枪啊
- Are you sure about that? - Go ahead, shoot.
但可能不是上上之策
But it might not be the best idea...
毕竟只有我知道 你马子被绑在哪里
...seeing as how I'm the only one who knows where your chiquita's tied up.
犸丽在哪里？
Where is Maricruz?
告诉你，还不如直接杀了我
If I tell you, I'm as good as dead.
当然如果你开枪 她也死定了
Of course, if you shoot, so is she.
-你在唬人 -是吗？
- You're bluffing. - Am I?
让我用言语 让你看清现在的情况
Let me tell you in words you might be more familiar with.
她在洞里 里面有约三周的食物和水
She's in the hole. Enough food and water to last about three weeks.
之后，你可爱的小蜜桃
Any longer than that, your sweet little plum's...
就会变成葡萄干
...gonna dry up like a raisin.
-如果她出事，上帝帮助我K -帮助你？
- Lf anything happens to her, so help me... - Help you?
在我看来，是你该帮助我
The way I see it, it's you who's gotta help me.
等我找到钱 你才见得到那女孩
You ain't getting your hands on that girl till I get my hands on that money.
看来我们要当伙伴了
Guess that makes us partners.
清除所有障碍物
Clear the dock of any obstructions.
要出发了
Here we go.
她还没来
She's not here.
（限速三十里）
（风城甜甜圈）
喂？
Yeah?
莎拉，怎么回事？ 船要开了
Sara, what's the matter? The ship is leaving.
（五十八号、五十九号码头 五十六、五十七号码头）
-迈克K -怎么了？
- Michael... - What's wrong?
莎拉？
Sara?
我已经上船了
I'm already onboard.
抱歉，我没看到你 你在哪里？
I'm sorry, I must've just missed you. Where are you?
-我们在甲板上 -好
- We're on deck. - Great.
我上去找你，我爱你
I'm on my way up. Love you.
没事吧？
We good?
没事
Yeah.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
该死
Son of a bitch.
你可以聘请律师 如果负担不起
You have the right to an attorney. If you cannot afford an attorney...
法院会指派给你
...one will be provided for you.
他在哪里？
Where is he?
-我不知道 -别闹了莎拉
- I don't know. - No more games, sara.
-你正要去见他 -我没有
- You were on your way to see him. - No, I wasn't.
难道你只是想逃离 联邦探员的追捕？
You were just compelled to flee the custody of a federal agent?
后方l线已松开 准备放下
All lines astern are loose, Prepare for cast off,
我找不到她
I couldn't find her.
莎拉K我们得回去
Sara. We gotta go back.
-你帮不了忙的 -我们一定可以帮忙
- There's nothing you can do. - Always something we can do.
这次不行
Not this time.
这次你帮不了，没救了
Not this time. It's done.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
-要他还是坐牢？ -我只想吃甜甜圈
- Scofield or prison? - I just wanted a doughnut.
买甜甜圈给她 帮忙一下好吗？
Get her a doughnut. Can we get her one?
买一堆甜甜圈给她！ 把她关起来
Get her a doughnut. Get her a dozen doughnuts. Lock her up.
片名：越狱风云
剧名：巴拿马
（一周后）
五月K新墨西哥
May, May, May, New Mexico.
（五月三十日，亚布兹死亡 费朋纳兹的旅馆）
不要K
Don't, don't, don't...
你到底跑哪儿去了，迈克？
Where the hell did you go, Michael?
曼宏到底跑哪儿去了？
So where the hell is Mahone?
不知道 他已经失踪约一个礼拜
I don't know. He's been MIA for the last week or so.
他知道我在调查他的底细吗？
You think he knows I've been barking up one of his trees?
富兰克林先生，午安
Mr. Franklin, good afternoon.
这位是理查索伦斯 调查局风纪部组长
This is Richard sullins, director of internal affairs at the FBI.
这代表当我们的人做错事时
Which means whenever one of our people does something wrong...
修正是我的责任
...it's my job to make it right.
能修得多正？
How right are we talking about?
我们坦白一点
Well, let's be clear.
你是一个重罪犯
You are a convicted felon.
你从州立监狱逃出 我能帮忙的有限
You broke out of a state penitentiary. I can only do so much.
那我能说的也有限
Well, there's only so much I can say.
如果觉得我不相信你们 很抱歉
Now, I'm sorry if I seem a little bit skeptical...
因为上次 一个联邦探员跟我交易时
...but the last time a federal agent came up in here offering me a deal...
他给我一条绳子 而且要我套在脖子上
...there was a string attached that I was supposed to put around my neck.
上级已同意让你减刑
I've been authorized to offer you a reduced sentence...
只要你肯作证举发曼宏探员
...in exchange for your testimony against Agent Mahone.
从十八年减刑为十八个月
Instead of 18 years, you get 18 months.
十八个月？
Eighteen months?
你们知道那家伙想杀我吗？
Hey, you know what? That man tried to kill me.
只要他察觉我密告
So as soon as he finds out that I'm singing...
我大概连十八天都活不成
...I probably won't even last 18 days.
-富兰克林先生K -他威胁我的家人
- Mr. Franklin... - He threatened my family.
我必须在外面保护她们
Now, I need to be out there protecting them.
所以在你提供这种条件之前 休想叫我作证
So until you can offer me something like that, I'm not testifying to a damn thing.
警卫
Guard.
自由之身
Free man.
你和家人
You and your family.
证人保护，全新人生
Witness protection, fresh start.
-前科一笔勾消？ -干净溜溜
- Clean record? - Spick-and-span.
白纸黑字写出来 我就作证
You put that in writing and you got yourself a witness.
长官？
Sir?
我有敲门，但K
I knocked, but...
你没事吧？
You okay?
你觉得这像什么？这里
What does that look like to you? There, right there.
-一个三角型 -对，我之前也这么想
- It's a triangle. - Yeah, I thought so too.
这个呢？这里
How about this? Right there.
这是圆周率的数学记号
It's the mathematical symbol for pi.
三点一四 我猜是日期、区码
Three-point-one-four. I'm thinking date, area code.
三一四是密苏里 你认为斯科菲尔德在那里吗？
Three-one-four, that's Missouri. So you think scofield's there?
不太可能 你懂希腊字母吗，兰恩探员？
I doubt it. How's your Greek alphabet, Agent Lang?
我不确定，应该K
I don't know. I guess it's...
如果三角形其实是 第四个希腊字母，还有K
What if I told you that triangle was a delta? And that this...
这记号不是圆周率 而是字母呢？
This here was not the symbol pi, but the letter.
刺青的照片上没有这些记号
I didn't see those in the photos of the tattoos.
刺青上没有 这些是他原本的设计图
They weren't. We pulled these from his original sketches.
从硬碟上取得的
They're off the hard drive.
斯科菲尔德的逃亡计划有步骤 所以他才能掌控一切
Scofield numbered the steps of his escape. That's how he kept everything in order.
但看来他不是用数字 而是用字母，例如K
But it looks like that he didn't use numbers, that he used letters, like...
“艾伦施韦策”刺青的设计图
The sketch of this tattoo. Allen schweitzer.
标着第一个希腊字母 也就是计划第一步
Marked with an alpha, first letter of the Greek alphabet. First step in his plan.
第五个字母 计划中的第五步骤
Epsilon, fifth letter of the Greek alphabet. Fifth step in his plan.
还有第八、第十个字母
Here's theta, kappa.
这个，第十九个字母 到边境，对吧？
How about that? Tau. Be at the border, right?
-快结束了，还听得懂吗？ -所以你认为K
- Getting closer to the end. You with me? - So you think...
他的第二十四个字母
His omega.
-希腊字母最后一个 -就是他计划的最终步骤
- The last letter of the Greek alphabet... - Is the last step of his plan.
这是什么？花里的耶稣？
What is that? Christ in a flower?
-玫瑰 -还有数字，六一七
- Rose. - And these numbers, 617.
可能是圣经，第六章十七节
Could be biblical. Chapter six, verse 17.
六一七，六月十七号
Six-one-seven, 617. June 17th.
-今天几号？ -十五号
- Oh, what's today? - Fifteenth.
-所以不管最终步骤是什么 -就在两天之后
- So whatever his last step is... - It's gonna happen in two days.
（墨西哥市，墨西哥观光局）
我们的资料里没有史戴摩先生
你应该去问公车和租车公司
-他说什么？ -没什么，跟其他人一样
- What's he saying? - Nothing, the same as the rest.
也许他不了解 移民局的西班牙文怎么说？
Maybe he don't comprende, What's spanish for INs?
别傻了，这里是墨西哥 犯法的人是你
Don't be stupid. We're in Mexico. You're the illegal one here.
这不代表他没有家人在美国 正想尽办法弄张绿卡
It doesn't mean he ain't got family up north trying to clean their way to a green card.
他很清楚我在说什么
He knows what I'm talking about.
我讨厌这美国佬
可是我需要他
我的女友和孩子遇上麻烦
我们要找的这个人K
只有他能够救我的家人
他用E史戴摩这个名字
拜托，如果你有消息
请打这支电话
我会永远感激你
（墨西哥市，美天饭店）
你对我真好，小苏珊
Oh, you are too good to me, suzy-Q.
我最爱的喝法
Just how I like it.
我怎会如此幸运？
How did I get so lucky?
不，泰迪熊 幸运的人是我
Oh, no, Teddy Bear. I'm the lucky one.
自从我遇见你那天起
The day I met you...
我就重生了
...was the day I was born.
-时间到了 -不，苏珊
- We're out of time. - No, susan.
我们有一生的时间共享
We got our whole lives together.
不，我是说时间到了
No, I mean the hour is up.
我会好好犒赏你好吗？
I'll take care of you plenty, okay?
既然都到这地步了 让我们继续吧
It's just, we're rolling here, so let's, you know, get back.
你想干嘛，美女？
How's the... What's cooking, good-Iooking?
我真的觉得 你事先付钱会比较好
I would really feel better if you paid me up-front.
我已经先告诉你 如果你听我的，我就会犒赏你
I told you up-front that if you did this right, I would take care of you, so...
你付了一小时的钱
You paid me for an hour.
一小时到了
The hour's up.
如果要我留下 我要更多钱
If you want me to stay, I need more money.
太好了 气氛被你毁了，感谢
Great. Great, you ruined it. Thanks.
我刚刚还认为 “这马子挺聪明的”
You know, for a second, I was like, "This chick has a brain in her head."
不过如果属实 你就不会当妓女了，对吧？
Then, if you did, you wouldn't be a street whore, right?
我不认识小苏珊这贱人
You know, I don't know who this suzy-Q bitch is...
但难怪她不想和你有瓜葛
...but no wonder she wants nothing to do with you.
你刚刚骂她贱人？
You didn't just call her a bitch, did you?
好吧
Okay.
我数到三
I'm going to count to three.
如果你不把手放下 我就尖叫
And if you don't put your arm down, I'm going to scream.
一
One.
二
Two...
（巴拿马，克里斯多拔）
我们到了
We made it.
还没
Not yet.
我还得先见一个人
First, there's someone we need to see.
（六一七）
好，谁有头绪？
Okay, who's got what?
把耶稣比喻成玫瑰 是《圣经》持续出现的一个主题
Christ as a rose. It's a common theme that runs through the Bible.
马丁路德将它用作教派的教徽
Martin Luther adopted it, his coat of arms.
还有对耶稣死而复生的信仰
And there's a belief that Christ rose from the dead.
既然这是斯科菲尔德的最后一步 代表新生命，可能是这意思
And since this is scofield's final step, a new life, could be something there.
你，把他们说的写在白板上
You, keep track of this on the board. On the board.
-卫勒在哪里？ -我查到这些资料
- Where's Wheeler? - Here we go.
印度安那州 新哈莫尼第一批居民
Harmonists. First settlers of New Harmony, Indiana.
把黄金玫瑰当成耶稣的记号
Used a golden rose as their symbol for Christ.
-真有用啊 -有种花叫耶诞玫瑰
- That's a reach. - There's a flower called the Christmas rose.
耶稣玫瑰不就是纳粹K
Wasn't Christ Rose the German code name...
引发突出部之役 那次反攻的代号？
...for the counterattack by the Nazis that led to the Battle of the Bulge?
地点在哪里？
Where was that?
阿尔登森林 在比利时和德国边境
Ardennes Forest. On the Belgium-Germany border.
如果他们找得到 那里是不错的藏匿点
Not a bad place to hide, if they can find it.
你深入调查好吗？
So you gonna look into that?
-好 -好，还有什么？
- Yeah. - All right, what else?
耶稣在春分后 第一个周日复活
Christ potentially rose from the dead on Easter.
-复活节？ -复活节誓约组织？
- Easter sunday? - Easter seals?
（耶诞玫瑰、耶稣玫瑰）
斯科菲尔德的档案在哪儿？
Who's got scofield's file?
这里
Here we go.
（艾度柏劳，状况不明）
（克利丝汀娜玫瑰斯科菲尔德 死亡）
玫瑰里的耶稣
Christ in a rose.
-对，怎么了？ -斯科菲尔德母亲的名字
- Yeah, what about it? - Scofield's mother's name.
克利丝汀娜玫瑰斯科菲尔德
"Christina Rose" scofield.
我以为她已经死了
But I thought she was dead.
我也这样以为
Well, so did I.
So did I.
他们从福克斯河越狱出来 斯科菲尔德做的第一件事
First thing that scofield did when they broke out of Fox River...
就是去坟墓挖出 藏好的用品
...is pick up supplies that he had stashed in a grave.
我要你去查 斯科菲尔德的母亲埋在哪里
I want you to find out where scofield's mother's buried.
然后呢？
And what?
-看她是否真的埋在里面 -是，长官
- And see if she's buried. - Yes, sir.
-巴拿马呢？ -巴拿马怎么了？
- What about Panama? - What about Panama?
他的硬碟里有 大量巴拿马的资料
We found his hard drive. It was full of information about Panama in particular.
他知道硬碟在你手上 这家伙的确傲慢
Which he knows you have. Guy's got all kinds of hubris.
但他不会笨到 明知你会去等他，还去那个国家
But he's smart enough to stay out of a country where he knows you'll be waiting.
除非那里有他需要的东西
Unless there's something there that he needs.
或某人
Or someone.
给我巴拿马的地图
I want a map of Panama.
还有调查斯科菲尔德的母亲 克莉丝汀娜玫瑰
And find out if scofield's mom, Christina Rose...
在中美是否有家人、土地 任何的关联
...has any family in Central America, any property, anything.
我上次搭这种公车时 是要去福克斯河
Last time I was in a bus like this I was heading to Fox River.
这国家真棒
Man, this country's amazing.
风景真美
It's beautiful.
-那是什么味道？ -香蕉和甘蔗
- What's that smell, man? - Bananas and sugar cane.
巴拿马主要输出品
It's Panama's biggest exports.
别这样，老弟
Come on, man.
我们刚逃出来 你就一直在聊巴拿马和烂公车
You've been talking about Panama and bumpy bus rides ever since we broke out.
-现在真正搭上来了K -她应该和我们在一起
- And now we're actually doing it... - she should've been here with us.
要救她，以后时间多得是
We got all the time in the world for that.
-之后你和莎拉K -我们到了再说好吗？
- Someplace down the track, you and sara... - Can we just get there, please?
当然
Sure.
目前查不到斯科菲尔德母亲 和巴拿马的关联性
So far, no hits on any connection between scofield's mother and Panama.
不过有三十八位不同组合的 克莉丝汀娜玫瑰
But there are 38 listings of Christina Rose in various combinations...
姓、名、中间名顺序不同
...of first name, middle name and last name.
好，把名字和刺青上的 六一七交叉比对
All right, cross-reference the names with the number 617 from the tattoo.
也许不是日期 看是否是住址
Maybe it's not a date. See if it's an address.
-知道了 -有消息就通知大使馆
- Got it. - Lf anybody pops, call the embassy.
请他们派人逮捕这女人 并侦讯她
Have them send an officer to pick up the woman for questioning.
我们无权逮捕外国公民 如果没有K
I don't think we can just arrest a foreign citizen without...
爱国者法案，你祖母做手工 少绣一针我也可以逮捕她
Patriot Act. I could arrest your grandmother for missing a stitch in her macrame.
如果有人帮助斯科菲尔德 无论死活，我都要知道
If anybody's helping scofield, dead or alive, I wanna know who they are.
就是她？
That her?
对
Yeah.
你好，瓦士奎太太
Hola, Mrs. Vasquez.
你迟到了 比你说的日期晚太多了
You are late. It's much later than the date you said.
我们遇到了一点麻烦
Well, we ran into a little bit of trouble.
他是哪位？
Who is this?
我的合伙人
It's a business associate.
克莉丝汀娜玫瑰 我还记得
Christina Rose. I remember.
这里可以找到她
You will find her here.
我们在外头碰面
I'll meet you outside.
我有事忘了问
I forgot to ask something.
好
All right.
我可以借用电话吗？
Do you have a phone I could use?
是，我要打国际线
Yes, I need an international operator, please.
美国
United states.
电话是312-346K
It's 312-346...
-你在搞什么鬼？ -打电话
- What are you doing? - Making a phone call.
你不能打
You can't.
我们甚至不知她是死是活
We don't even know if she's alive.
如果莎拉被逮捕 手机就在他们手上
If sara's in custody, they got her phone.
你想被逮吗？
You wanna get caught?
-喂 -我讨厌三件事，亚历
- Yeah? - Three things I hate, Alex.
塞车、曲棍球 和不断打电话问你相同的问题
Traffic, hockey, and calling you with the same question over and over.
那就别再打来 但我想那对兄弟在巴拿马
Then don't call me anymore. But I believe the brothers are in Panama.
-是吗？ -正确地点在斯科菲尔德的刺青上
- Is that so? - The key to where is on scofield's tattoos.
虽然很高兴你把范围 缩小到一个国家
While I'm thrilled you've narrowed it down to a country...
这不是我打来的目的
...that's not why we're talking.
班哲明迈尔斯富兰克林还活着
Benjamin Miles Franklin is alive.
这我知道
I'm aware of that, yeah.
而且即将被释放
And being released from custody.
不可能 需要我的办公室同意才行
Not possible. They would need permission from my office.
很高兴你掌控着大局
Good to know you're on top of things.
叫卫勒探员来找我
Find me Agent Wheeler.
你可以去见他了
He'll see you now.
请恕我直说，长官 难道不能在我的办公室谈吗？
Forgive me for asking, sir, but couldn't we be doing this in my office?
那样会舒适许多
It'd be much more comfortable.
我认为有必要开天窗说亮话
I felt we needed to speak freely.
接下来几小时内 这里是K
For the next several hours, this is what those...
情报单位所谓的盲点
...in the intelligence community refer to as a blind spot.
听说是受到太阳位置的影响
Something to do with the position of the sun, I'm told.
长距离录音设备会受到干扰
Disrupts long-distance recording devices.
长官，我再次致歉
If I may apologize again, sir...
总统事件的结局不尽理想
...for the unfortunate outcome with the president.
我知道她对我们很重要 我保证下一步K
I know how important she was to our interests. I assure you that moving forward...
不准你移动一步 直到你能K
You won't be moving anywhere until you can explain to me...
解释出了什么事为止
...how this happened.
这对兄弟
The brothers.
-他们让K -他们还活着？
- They're making it... - still alive?
是，显然他们已经逃离国内
Yes. It appears they were able to flee the country.
逃到哪里？
To where?
曼宏先生认为他们在巴拿马
Mr. Mahone seems to believe they're in Panama.
曼宏先生知道 他们在巴拿马的确切位置吗？
Does our Mr, Mahone know where exactly in Panama they are?
还不知道，怎么了？
Not yet. Why?
你对索拿了解多少，金先生？
How much do you know about sona, Mr. Kim?
只了解上级透露给我的资讯
Only what I've been given clearance on.
也许在这种情况下 我们需要改变策略
Perhaps what our situation requires is a change in strategy.
法院要多久才会批准逮捕令？
How long till the court approves the arrest warrant?
马上就来 只要等起诉书出炉
Any time now, Just waiting for the indictment to come down,
好，我有个问题
okay. Well, I've got a question for you.
他如果在怎么办？ 我不能一直躲着他
What if he's in there? I can't keep avoiding him.
他会看穿人心 这是他的工作
He reads people. That's what he does.
如果他发现我也牵扯在内 我就需要保护K
If he finds out I'm involved, I'm gonna need protection from...
卫勒，别紧张，深呼吸
Wheeler, relax. Take a breath.
曼宏只看得懂你写给他的资料 你可以装得很正常吗？
The only thing Mahone can read is what you write for him. Can you act normal?
只要这样就好
That's all you have to do,
现在别惊动他，让他跑了
We don't want him to get spooked and take off,
这件事马上就会结束
This is all gonna be over soon,
好吧，谢谢
All right. Thank you.
不，应该谢你才对
No. Thank you.
卫勒
Wheeler.
你上哪儿去了？
Where you been?
我必须这样做
I gotta do this.
你在干嘛，亚历？ 我身上没有窃听器
What are you doing, Alex? I'm not wearing a wire.
-告诉我怎么回事好吗？ -在古代的英国K
- You gonna tell me what's going on here? - In old England...
背叛是要被砍头的
...the punishment for a traitorous act was beheading.
砍头之后 他们会把断头拉起来
Following the execution, they would hold up the severed head by the hair.
不是让群众看人头 而是让人头看群众
Not for the crowd to see the head, but for the head to see the crowd...
因为断头之后 意识还会停留八秒
...because consciousness sticks around for another eight seconds.
这是给叛国贼 再一次机会K
Idea was that it would give the traitor one more chance to take...
你不会想这么做的 你想想K
You don't wanna do this, okay? Just take a moment...
如果你要在背后捅我！ 卫勒探员K
If you're gonna stab me in the back, Agent Wheeler...
就该学聪明把刀子藏好
...be smart enough to cover up the knife.
这礼拜你去找富兰克林三次
You go and visit Franklin three times this week.
每天和索伦斯讲两次电话？
Called sullins, what, twice a day?
和我合作 都没让你长进一点吗？
Didn't you learn anything working for me?
一定要不露痕迹，除非K
You gotta cover your tracks, unless you...
除非你想被逮到
Unless you wanna get caught.
你想让我知道是你干的
You wanted me to know it was you.
-你是杀人凶手，亚历 -是吗？
- You're a killer, Alex. - Is that so?
你家院子的土壤样本 和奥斯卡席尔斯的失踪有关
Soil samples from your yard in connection with the disappearance of oscar shales.
鉴识科准备要提报 你枪杀大卫阿普斯基的K
Forensics is prepared to submit a report detailing the irregularities...
所有不合理之处
...in the shooting of David "Tweener" Apolskis.
还有约翰亚布兹被枪杀时 你公然漠视程序K
There's your blatant disregard for protocol in the death of John Abruzzi...
还有一个逃犯说 我叫他自杀，我知道
And the escaped con who says that I told him to kill himself, I know.
你以为他的证词 可以让你飞上青天吗？
You think his testimony is gonna send you to the Promised Land?
你也可以把我除掉
You can erase me too.
但你无法抹灭
But it's not gonna erase the very real fact...
你将在监狱度过余生的事实
...that you're gonna spend the rest of your life in prison.
你知道吗？
You know...
你让我想起刚上任的自己
You remind me of myself when I was a young agent.
什么？
What?
我真希望这句话是种称赞
I wish I could take that as a compliment.
你做得非常好，卫勒
That's some real fine work, Wheeler.
表现得很好
Good job, though.
千万别让人威胁你 做出不该做的事
Don't you let anyone scare you into doing the wrong thing.
让我带你到案
Let me take you in.
你捅了什么漏子 我们都可以处理
Whatever mess you're in, we can clean it up.
只有一种处理方法 只有一种
There's only one way to clean this. One way.
你有访客
Hey, you got a visitor.
-是谁？ -我不知道
- Yeah, who? - I don't know.
我只接到命令来带你
I was just instructed to bring you.
在告诉我是谁之前 我哪儿都不去，懂吗？
Hey, look, I ain't going nowhere until you tell me who it is I'm meeting, all right?
你们住手，听我说
You guys, just stop it. Listen to me for a second.
你只要出去看看就好
That's all you gotta do, go out and check.
那家伙看起来很高大
Look, the guy's kind of tall, okay?
至少可以帮这个忙吧？
It's the least that you can do, huh?
-什么K？ -爸爸
- What the? - Daddy.
天啊
Oh, my God.
过来
Come here.
爸爸好爱你
Daddy loves you so much.
是真的吗？
So is it real?
他说你可以出狱 而且我们不用再逃亡了
He says you're gonna go free, that we don't have to run anymore.
-怎么回事？他们K -别紧张K
- I mean, what happened? What changed? - Hey, hey, hey.
你不用担心
Now, don't you worry about it.
只要知道你的男人 有两把刷子
You just know that your man handles things.
对吧？没错
Ain't that right? That's right.
好吧，我不相信，但很好
Okay. I don't believe it, but okay.
班哲明，我要跟你谈一下
Benjamin, if I could just have a quick word.
好K
Yeah. Hey...
你们到走廊那边等我，好吗？
Why don't you go down the hall for just a quick second, okay?
-我马上过去 -好
- I'll be right there. - Okay.
东西在这儿
Here it is.
新住址、新身份
New address, new identities.
检察官会和你保持联络 讨论你的证词
The prosecutor's gonna be in touch to go over your testimony.
你只要在他指定的 时间、地点出现
So you just make sure you show up where he says and when he says.
好K
Yeah, okay, okay.
我是自由之身吧？
But I'm a free man, right?
自由之身
Free man.
等等，曼宏怎么办？
Oh, wait a minute. What about Mahone, you know?
我不想余生 都得小心翼翼过活
I don't wanna be looking over my shoulder for the rest of my life.
曼宏的事由我担心 你只需担心别惹上麻烦
You let me worry about Mahone. You just worry about staying out of trouble.
绝对不会有问题的 相信我
Hey, you ain't gonna have a problem with that. Trust me.
别搞砸了
Don't screw it up.
还有多远？
How much further?
不远
Not far.
你该知道，莎拉是自愿的
You know, for what it's worth, no one forced sara to do what she did.
只要你觉得心安理得就好
Whatever gets you through the night.
这话什么意思？ 我又没有叫你利用她
What the hell does that mean? I didn't ask you to use her.
事情没那么单纯
It's not that simple.
-只要你觉得心安理得就好 -林克，知道什么让我很讶异吗？
- Whatever gets you through the night. - You know what amazes me, Linc?
你从不把事情放在心上 你从不在意
Nothing ever registers with you. Ever.
过了就算了，对吧？
It just rolls right off your back, doesn't it?
我们毁了莎拉的人生 你却仿佛不痛不痒
We ruin sara's life and it's like you don't even care.
-你这么认为？ -我们在这儿，莎拉在监牢里
- Is that what you think? - We're here, and sara's back in prison.
-这公平吗？ -当然不公平
- Does that seem fair? - None of it's fair.
-别一付失去女友的样子 -不然谁是重点？
- Don't make this about boy loses girl. - Who should it be about?
威莫兰？中间人？
Westmoreland? Tweener?
-罗杰？ -不要再说了
- L. J? - Let me stop you there.
记得我引发暴动时 被杀死的狱警名字吗？
Remember the name of the guard murdered because of the riot I started?
-闭嘴，迈克 -你记得他的名字吗？
- Shut up. - Do you even remember his name?
-闭嘴 -你应该记得哩诺卡吧？
- Shut up. - Bet you remember Veronica's, don't you?
-不准再提到她的名字！ -茶包呢？
- Mention her name again, I swear to God! - What about T-Bag?
他因为我们的关系 消遥法外！
He's out there now because of us.
都是因为你和我！
You and me.
他取走的每一条性命 都要算在我们头上
Every life he takes, that's blood on our hands.
都是为了什么？
And for what?
我并没有要你来救我
I didn't ask you to do what you did.
他们要杀你，林克
They were gonna kill you, Linc.
也许你该让他们得逞！
Well, maybe you should've let them.
收回这句话
Take that back.
虽然莎拉的遭遇我很内疚 但她有选择的余地
As bad as I feel about sara, she had a choice.
哩诺卡没有选择余地
Veronica didn't.
我听着她被杀，迈克
I listened to her die, Michael.
我听着她死去 我却无能为力
I listened to her die, and there was nothing I could do.
我救不了她
Nothing.
我们失去太多了
We've lost so much, man.
不能再失去彼此
We can't afford to lose each other.
不能再失去了
We just can't.
打算要出远门吗，亚历？
Going somewhere, Alex?
不知道，有吗？
I don't know. Am I?
别这样 你知道我不喜欢事必躬亲
Come on. You know I don't like to get my hands dirty.
当有充份原动力时 人能做出的行为真令人惊讶
It's surprising the things a man will do when properly motivated.
这句话是你告诉我的吧？
Wasn't it you who told me that?
我可以现在杀了你
You know, I would kill you right now...
只为得到一丝平静
...if I thought it would give me an ounce of peace.
什么事能给你平静？
And what would give you peace?
整个过程 我都设法保持冷静
I've been able to hold it together through all this...
因为原本还有出路可言
...because there was a light at the end of the tunnel.
有人生 在等我和我的家人
A life at the end of the tunnel for me, for my family.
现在呢？
And now what?
你有看到我儿子 我妻子的样子吗？
Do you see my son? Do you see my wife?
我得到什么？ 你给了我什么？
What have I got? What have you given me?
如果我告诉你K
What if I was to tell you...
有办法找回那条出路呢？
...that there was something that could turn that light back on?
你会怎么说？
What would you say?
我会说那是跟你拖我下水时 一样的烂话，你这浑蛋
I'd say that's the same offer you made when you dragged me into this.
瞧我得到什么 他们要把我公诸于世
And look where it's got me now. They're gonna drag me before the public.
他们要将我 像杀人犯一样起诉
They're gonna prosecute me like some kind of murderer.
他们手上的实证 是你无法湮灭的
There's evidence, really hard, tangible evidence that you can't take away.
你说的对
You're right.
但我可以帮你脱罪
But I can help you get away.
到了这节骨眼 你似乎别无选择
And at this point, I don't think you've got any other options.
西奥多“茶包”包威 在墨西哥被逮捕
Theodore "T-Bag" Bagwell was apprehended in Mexico.
我猜猜，你要我杀了他
Oh, let me guess, you want him dead.
不
Oh, no.
我们的策略有点改变
There's been a change in strategy.
我们要留他活口
We're gonna need him alive.
这是一个真正的终点，亚历
I'm talking about a very real finish line here, Alex.
你一路走来，很辛苦
You've come so far.
我还要再走多久？
How much further would I have to go?
算你走运
Well, you're lucky.
这次你只要去巴拿马
For this, you only have to go to Panama.
我正试图回想我们的人生 还有意义可言的时候
I'm trying to remember the last time our lives made any kind of sense.
妈过世之前 只有我们三人的时候
Before Mom died, when it was just the three of us.
她就在那里
Well, there she is.
你好，兰恩
Hello, Lang.
怎么回事？ 有黑衣人在翻你的办公室
What's going on? I mean, there's suits here going through your office.
我待会儿再解释
I'll explain later.
好吧
All right.
-看到传真了吗？ -没有，怎么了？
- Did you get the fax? - No, why?
你查到什么？
What do you got?
克莉丝汀娜玫瑰的资料 你应该会有兴趣
Information on christina Rose you might find interesting,
斯科菲尔德抢银行前四个月
Looks like she was commissioned about four months...
看来他委任一位名叫 安帕罗瓦士奎的工人搭建这艘船
...before scofield robbed that bank by a builder in Panama named Amparo Vasquez.
该死的家伙
Son of a bitch.
它真美
She's beautiful.
对，虽然它的能力有限K
Yeah, she's not the real thing, but...
要去哪里，老弟？
so where to, man?
想去哪儿都行
Anywhere we want.
（克莉丝汀娜玫瑰号，巴拿马）
真的结束了吗？
So is it really over?
对，宝贝，真的结束了
Yeah. Yeah, baby, it's really over.
好
Okay.
怎么了，宝贝？
What is it, baby?
没事
Nothing.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.
我们查过马里纳尔可的火车站 和普埃布拉的公车总站
Okay, so we checked the train station in Malinalco, the bus depot in Puebla...
还有几乎所有的饭店
...and just about every hotel there is.
喂K慢慢说，老兄
Hello. Hey, hey, hey, slow down, sancho.
找你的
For you.
你好
是观光局的员工 他找到他了
That was the guy from the tourism bureau. He found him.
在哪里？
Where?
有个E史戴摩 刚搭上往巴拿马市的飞机
An E. Stammel just boarded a plane to Panama City.
他去巴拿马干什么？
What the hell's he doing in Panama?
会说英文吗？
Speak English?
说“早安，泰迪”
Say, "Good morning, Teddy."
早安，泰迪
Good morning, Teddy.
好，你不会说英文
So then actually, no, you don't speak English.
有人会说英文吗？
Habla any ingles around here?
说“早安，泰迪”
Say, "Good morning, Teddy."
早安，泰迪
Good morning, Teddy.
说“早安，泰迪熊”
Say, "Good morning, Teddy Bear."
早安，泰迪熊
Good morning, Teddy Bear.
你喜欢假发吗？
You like wigs?
只要钱够多 我什么都喜欢
For the right money, I like anything.
没有消息
There's nothing.
网路上没有莎拉被捕的消息
Nothing online about sara's arrest.
也许他们不想曝光
Maybe they're keeping it quiet.
留言板呢？ 那个欧洲金翅网站
What about the message board? The Gold Finch thing.
只有百元钞票的留言和K 有苏克的讯息
Just something from C-Note, and there is a message from sucre.
他还在逃亡？
Still running, huh?
怎么了？
What?
苏克说茶包在这里 在巴拿马
Sucre says T-Bag's here, in Panama.
他怎么会知道？
How the hell did he know?
不知道 他说钱还在茶包手上
I don't know. He says, "The Bag still has the bag.
他在巴拿马市的终点旅馆
He's in Panama City at the Fin Del Camino Hotel.
如果你在那儿，想帮忙抓他 通知我一声，苏克留
If you're there and want to help put that bird back in the cage, let me know. Sucre."
-这浑蛋怎么会来巴拿马？ -我们得去抓他
What is that son of a bitch doing in Panama?
-别管他了，我们不需要钱 -不是为了钱，林克
- We gotta go after him. - Just let it be.
- We don't need the money. - It's not about the money, Linc.
只要茶包p遥法外 我们之后做的善事都没意义
Whatever good we do from here on out doesn't matter as long as T-Bag's out there.
-迈克，都走到这K -我做错太多事，我只希望K
- Michael, we made it. All we... - Much has gone wrong. If we could just...
我只希望这么一次 能做对的事情
if we could just make this right.
巴拿马市只有一个小时路程 而且已经知道他的下落
Panama City is only an hour away. And now we know where he's staying.
通知警察
Call the police.
我选巴拿马是有原因的 这里没有引渡条款
There's a reason I chose Panama. There's no extradition laws.
警察不会管他的
They're not gonna touch him.
那你想怎么做？
So, what are you gonna do?
我再想办法
I'll figure something out.
再想办法？ 你连上厕所都要计划，少来了
Figure it out? You don't take a piss without a plan, man. Come on.
我做事从不考虑 瞧我有什么下场
Look, I never think, and look where it got me.
对，你落到巴拿马 一艘满是酒的船上
Yeah, in Panama with a boatload of booze.
是你帮我的 我只害自己被判死刑
You got me that. I got me a death sentence.
听着，我们先出海 仔细考虑
Look, let's just get out to sea, think things through.
等时机对了 我们再做这件好事
When the time's right, we make it right.
可以吗？
Okay?
（我加入，到了通知我 迈克留）
（我明天到，到时见 苏克留）
巴拿马航空 前往巴拿马的二七一号班机
Trans-Panamanian Airlines flight 271 to Panama,,,
请头等舱的旅客登机
,,, now boarding all first-class passengers,
再宣布一遍 前往巴拿马市的旅客请登机
Again, we're boarding for Panama city,
到时见
see you soon.
有家真好
Home, sweet home.
酒拿来了 但莱姆汁好像坏掉了
I got the booze, but the limes are shot.
迈克？
Michael?
迈克！
Michael!
Michael.